Guide to the New York Building Congress Records WAG.167
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Photographs, 1936-2008
  - Subseries VI:B: Events, 1944-2008
    - Unidentified [Formal Luncheon?] Event (1), circa 1960s - 1970s (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified [Formal Luncheon?] Event (2), circa 1960s - 1970s (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified Forum, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Foundation Meeting: Prints and Negatives, Sep 27, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified Events, 1946-1963 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified Events, 1964 - 1979 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified Events: Negatives, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified Events, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified Events: Prints and Negatives, May 2000 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified Events (1), undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified Events (2), undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Events (3), undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified Events (4), undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified Events (5), undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified Party, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified Speaker, undated (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Visit to Battery Park City Site, Mar 13, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Subseries VI:C: Portraits, 1931-1988
    - General, undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - General: Negatives, undated (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Presidents (I), 1931-1969 (Box OS007, Folder 1)
    - Presidents (II), 1969-1987 (Box OS007, Folder 2)
    - A, 1971-1973, undated (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - B (Includes Styles Bridges), 1953-1974 (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - C (Includes Edward Carlough and Robert Cutler): Prints and Negatives, 1945-1976 (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - D (Includes Robert W. Dowling), 1953-1988 (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - E, 1961-1975, undated (Box 43, Folder 29)
    - F (Includes James Farley), 1953-1974, undated (Box 43, Folder 30)
    - G, 1960-1974, undated (Box 43, Folder 31)
    - H (Includes C. J. Haggerty, Charles Haines, Averell Harriman, Wallace K. Harrison and John F. Henning), 1936-1974, undated (Box 43, Folder 32)
    - I, undated (Box 43, Folder 33)
    - J, 1941-1967, undated (Box 43, Folder 34)
    - K: Prints and Negatives, 1965-1977, undated (Box 43, Folder 35)
    - L (Includes William L. Lauren, Arthur Levitt, Jr., and John V. Lindsay), 1962-1974 (Box 43, Folder 36)
    - M (Includes George Meany, Vice Admiral Ben Moreel, and Robert Moses), 1936-1975, undated (Box 43, Folder 37)
    - N (Includes Richard Nixon and Lauris Norstad), 1964-1971, undated (Box 43, Folder 38)
    - O (Includes William O'Dwyer), 1946-1975, undated (Box 43, Folder 39)
    - P, 1965-1975, undated (Box 43, Folder 40)
    - R (Includes Richard Ravitch and Nelson Rockefeller), 1947-1950, undated (Box 43, Folder 41)
    - S (Includes Emil Schram, Louis Skidmore and Cardinal Francis Skidmore), 1941-1979 (Box 43, Folder 42)
    - T (Includes Bertram Tallamy, Thomas Thacher, Austin Tobin and John Tunney), 1936-1974 (Box 43, Folder 43)
    - U, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 44)
    - V, 1966, undated (Box 43, Folder 45)
    - W (Includes Robert F. Wagner, Jr., Robert Weaver, Casper Weinberger, Grover Whalen and Malcolm Wilson), 1959-1977 (Box 43, Folder 46)
    - Z, 1948, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 47)
  - Subseries VI:D: Site Photographs, 1948-1974
    - Construction Sites: Slides and Negatives, undated (Box 43, Folder 48)
    - Demonstration of Honeywell Indoor Air Quality Diagnositics: Prints and Slides, undated (Box 43, Folder 49)
    - Images of Albany, NY (Aerial), Jun 14, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 50)
    - NYBC Offices (Interior), 1948-1949 (Box 43, Folder 51)
  - Subseries VI:E: Other Formats and Oversize, 1943-1988
    - Rolled Photograph (Fun and Frolic) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], Dec 18, 1952 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Rolled Photograph (Fun and Frolic) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], 1953 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Rolled Photograph (Fun and Frolic) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], 1954 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Rolled Photograph (Fun and Frolic) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], 1956 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Rolled Photograph (Gillroy Luncheon) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Rolled Photographs (Joint Luncheon, NYBC and Producers' Council, Inc. (Hotel Baltimore); Fall Meeting of the Producers' Council, Inc.) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], Nov 11, 1943, Nov 29, 1944; Oct 2, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Rolled Photograph (Unidentified) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Rolled Photographs (Unidentified) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Rolled Photographs (Unidentified) [Restricted, consult Tamiment staff], undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Breakfast: Contact Sheets, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - First Leadership Awards Luncheon (Grand Hyatt Hotel, Includes Ed Koch, Arthur Levitt, Jr. and RobertF. Wagner, Jr.), Mar 29, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Fun and Frolic, Dec 19, 1944; Dec 18, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Fun and Frolic: Contact Sheets, 1979; 1980 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - New York City Municipal Building, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Portraits, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Seminar (Grand Hyatt Hotel): Contact Sheets, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Stereo Slides (1), 1952 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Stereo Slides (2), 1952 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Stereo Slides (3), 1952 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Stereo Slides (4), 1953 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Stereo Slides (5), 1953 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Stereo Slides (6), 1953 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Stereo Slides (7), 1953 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Stereo Slides (8), 1953 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Stereo Slides (9), 1953 (Box 46, Folder 9)
- Series VII: Audio-Visual Materials, 1987-2004
  Series VII: Audio-Visual Materials, 1987-2004 contains VHS videotapes and audio cassettes of various events.
  - Subseries VII:A: Audiocassettes, 1987-1997
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #1, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #2, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #3, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #4, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #5, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #6, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape #7: Art Fox (closing), Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Rebuilding New York Conference Tape: Lunch Speakers, Oct 13, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Louis Coletti on "Dialogue 101" (WCBS New York), 5am-5:30am, Jan 14, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Richard T. Anderson on WABC, 5:05pm`, Jun 10, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Subseries VII:B: Video (VHS), 2001-2004
    - Senator Hillary Rodham Clinton speaking at NYBC Luncheon Forum, Apr 30, 2001 (Box WAG ACCESS 1, Box 24, Folder 11)
    - NYBC World Trade Center Video (9/11 stills, footage, commentary; unidentified speakers), Nov 9, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - NYBC Dinner, Oct 23, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Leadership Awards Luncheon Video Presentation, May 20, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: Unprocessed Materials, 1985-2017
  Series VIII: Unprocessed Materials, 1985-2017 contains materials related to the Industry Recognition Dinners and Leadership Awards Luncheons, public relations and membership, and the Council of Presidents, as well as photographs, publications, and VHS tapes from various events. This series also includes daily planners kept by NYBC President Richard T. Anderson from 1994-2016.
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  - VHS Tapes of NYBC Events and Informational Programs, circa 1988-early 2000s (Box 25)
  - VHS Tapes of NYBC Events and Informational Programs; Four Cassette Tapes of News Programs, Events, and Public Service Announcements; a CD titled "Urbanomics Presentation for the Manhattan Institute"; and Six DVDs of NYBC Dinners and "Women in Construction" Program, circa 1985-2011 (Box 26)
  - Industry Recognition Dinners and Leadership Awards Luncheons, 1990s (Box 27)
  - Industry Recognition Dinners, Membership Survey, and Annual Reports, 1990s-2011 (Box 28)
  - Council of Presidents Meetings; Public Relations Materials; Membership Reports and Letters; NYC Olympic Bid Presentation; Industry Recognition Dinners; and Contact Sheets from Various Events, 1990-2001 (Box 29)
  - Photographs and Negatives from Various Events, 1998-2001, undated (Box 30)
  - Photographs, 2002-2006, undated (Box 31)
  - Photographs, Picture CD, and Audio CD, early 2000s (Box 32)
  - Minutes, 1921-1989 (Box 33)
  - 2016 Accretion: NYBC Membership Directories, 2011-2014 (Box 47)
  - 2016 Accretion: ENR New York, 2011-2014 (Box 47)
  - 2016 Accretion: New York Construction, 2003-2007 (Box 47, Box 48)
  - 2016 Accretion: New York Construction News, 1997-2003 (Box 48, Box 49)
  - 2016 Accretion: After the Fall, 2002 May 26 (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Con Ed Footage, 2002-2005 (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Gargano Raw Footage, undated (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Industry Recognition Dinner, Chuck Schumer, 2002 October 24 (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Industry Recognition Dinner, George Pataki, 2006 October 11 (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Jimmy Jones Interview, 2003 (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Marilyn Jordan Taylor Off Camera Voice Over, 2003 (Box 50)
  - 2016 Accretion: Hillary Clinton Dinners and Luncheons, 2002-2004 (Box 51)
  - 2016 Accretion: Luncheon on Transit News Magazine, 2004 (Box 51)
  - 2016 Accretion: OEM on PILE, 2001 (Box 51)
  - 2016 Accretion: Peckar, Rudin, and Malloy Tribute, 2002 October 24 (Box 51)
  - 2016 Accretion: Skanska, 2000 (Box 51)
  - 2016 Accretion: World Trade Center Tributes, 2002-2004 (Box 52, Box 53)
  - 2016 Accretion: NYBC Luncheon and Dinner Video Recordings, 2001-2008 (Box 54, Box 55)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Administrative Documents, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Board Meetings, 2011-2015 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Committee and Task Force Meetings, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Events, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Executive Committee, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Management Commitee, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Media, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Membership, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: New York Building Foundation, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Nominating Committee, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: PAC, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Policy and Advocacy, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Publications, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2016 Accretion: Electronic Records: Past Videos, 2011-2015; TW_WAG_167_1 (Disk TW_WAG_167_1)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 1994-1997 (Box 60)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 1998-2001 (Box 61)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 2002-2004 (Box 62)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 2005-2008 (Box 63)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 2008-2010 (Box 64)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 2011-2013 (Box 65)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Daily Planners, 2014-2016 (Box 66)
  - 2017 Accretion: Membership Directories, 1982-2012 (Box 67, Box 68)
  - 2017 Accretion: Legislative Bulletins, 1970s (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - 2017 Accretion: Nominating Committee, 1950s-1970s (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - 2017 Accretion: Luncheons, 1980s (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - 2017 Accretion: Task Force for Review of NYC Governmental Procedures Relative to Construction, 1978 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - 2017 Accretion: Awards Luncheons, 1997-1999 (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
  - 2017 Accretion: Industry Recognition Dinner, 1997-2016 (Box 69, Folder 7-9)
  - 2017 Accretion: NYBC Annual Reports, 2001-2010 (Box 69, Folder 10-11)
  - 2017 Accretion: Trade Publications, 2009-2015 (Box 69, Folder 12-17)
  - 2017 Accretion: Responsibility on Construction Jobs, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - 2017 Accretion: Subcommittee of Building Industry Practices, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - 2017 Accretion: Correspondence, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 20)
  - 2017 Accretion: The Impact of the Current Insurance Industry Crisis on NYC's Construction Industry, 2004 (Box 69, Folder 21)
  - 2017 Accretion: Builders of New York, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 22)
  - 2017 Accretion: Richard T. Anderson Photos (Box 69, Folder 23)
  - 2017 Accretion: Photographs, 1994-2016 (Box 69, Folder 24-26, Box 70)
  - 2017 Accretion: P.S. 147 Plaque, 2009 (Box 69, Folder 27)
  - 2017 Accretion: Video Recordings of NYBC Events, 2002-2011 (Box 71, Box 72)
  - 2017 Accretion: Board of Education Award, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - 2017 Accretion: Newspapers, 1971-2017 (Box 73, Folder 3-4)
- Series IX: Archived Website, Mar 14, 2009-ongoing
  The New York Building Congress, founded in 1921, is a coalition of 400 constituent organizations comprising more than 250,000 skilled trades people and professionals that works to advance economic and infrastructure investment and job creation. The Congress publishes reports and analysis related to building projects in New York City. The Congress also created the New York Building Foundation, which promotes research, education, and philanthropy in the construction industry. The website contains reports, committee and council information, and event listings.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
- Series X: Richard T. Anderson Papers, 1980-2015; 2 linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  This accretion to the New York Building Congress Records (dated 1980-2015) consists of materials created and collected by Richard T. Anderson, former NYBC President and Director Emeritus focused on RTA Advisory Services. Materials in this series include correspondence, NYBC meeting agendas and minutes, reports from annual NYBC membership meetings, newspaper clippings on topics concerning urban spaces and construction, and materials related to Anderson's professional relationships with adjacent organizations. The bulk of this series consists of transcripts of remarks given by Anderson before municipal bodies and other interest groups concerning subjects such as urban planning, re-zoning and development, public transportation, and specific New York City buildings, such as the New York Stock Exchange and the Javits Center expansion.
  - Richard T. Anderson Papers, 1980-2015 (Box 58, Box 59, Box 73, Folder 1)